<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Applied Caffeine</title>
    <link>https://appliedcaffeine.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Applied Caffeine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://appliedcaffeine.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>An ode to commode design</title>
      <link>https://appliedcaffeine.org/blog/gulf-of-execution/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://appliedcaffeine.org/blog/gulf-of-execution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A quick example regarding the importance of affordances and the gulf of execution in design. Examples can be found in all sorts of places.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computational exploration of mental models using model checking</title>
      <link>https://appliedcaffeine.org/blog/dissertation-topic-mental-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://appliedcaffeine.org/blog/dissertation-topic-mental-models/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For my dissertation, I&amp;rsquo;m arguing that we should be able to formally model and analyze human mental models to find unanticipated problems in computer security. But what does that mean and why does it matter?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I activated, then disabled, Google Analytics</title>
      <link>https://appliedcaffeine.org/blog/disabling-google-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://appliedcaffeine.org/blog/disabling-google-analytics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I first started my website, I was excited to use Google Analytics to examine my site traffic. However, I&amp;rsquo;ve since reversed my decision and ended up disabling it. Read on to find out why.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easy tips for improving your morning coffee</title>
      <link>https://appliedcaffeine.org/blog/easy-coffee-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://appliedcaffeine.org/blog/easy-coffee-tips/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, the New York Times ran a piece in their Food section called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2016/02/23/dining/how-to-make-coffee.html&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Three Steps to Brewing a Better Cup of Coffee&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; that I recently ran across. The author noted three steps you can take to improve the quality of your morning cup, but there are some other items I would like to add that can definitely improve the brewing process.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human Factors Engineering 100</title>
      <link>https://appliedcaffeine.org/blog/humanfactors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://appliedcaffeine.org/blog/humanfactors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As you can read on my &amp;ldquo;About&amp;rdquo; page, I&amp;rsquo;m a graduate student studying Human Factors (HF) engineering. What does that mean? Or, more importantly, what does and does not fall under the purview of my interests?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://appliedcaffeine.org/blog/hitomi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://appliedcaffeine.org/blog/hitomi/</guid>
      <description>Title: Human error and the Hitomi X-Ray Satellite Date: 2016-05-05 Category: blog Slug: human-error-and-hitomi Tags: human factors Summary: Within human factors engineering, one of the topics I&amp;rsquo;m most interested in is how human error can contribute to system failure. With news of JAXA&amp;rsquo;s loss of their just-launched x-ray satellite, did human error contribute to this complex system failure as well?
Within human factors engineering, one of the topics I&amp;rsquo;m most interested in is how human error can contribute to system failure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://appliedcaffeine.org/blog/keepassx/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://appliedcaffeine.org/blog/keepassx/</guid>
      <description>Title: Managing passwords with KeePassX and Syncthing Date: 2016-05-10 Category: blog Slug: using-keepassx-and-syncthing Tags: tutorials Summary: Improve your operational security by moving to a locally-stored password generation and storage utility.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to improve my digital operational security for the past three or four years, and this has included a lot of tutorial, forum, and Reddit browsing. The amount of information you can find on ways to keep yourself safe online is daunting, but one of the most challenging aspects of this effort is the separation of good advice from bad (and believe me, there&amp;rsquo;s a lot more of the bad than the good).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://appliedcaffeine.org/blog/latexvita/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://appliedcaffeine.org/blog/latexvita/</guid>
      <description>Title: Making a vita with LaTeX Date: 2016-04-05 Category: blog Slug: latexvita Tags: tutorials Summary: For those of you who would like to create a better-looking curriculum vitae for prospective employers, consider using moderncv. This tutorial will help you get started.
I have to admit, one of the principal reasons for building the site is to have a personalized space on the internet that people (and potential employers) can use to get a sense of me as a potential employee.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://appliedcaffeine.org/blog/malabar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://appliedcaffeine.org/blog/malabar/</guid>
      <description>Title: India Monsooned Malabar Date: 2016-04-17 Category: blog Slug: malabar Tags: coffee Summary: Of all the dark roast coffees that I&amp;rsquo;ve tried, the monsooned Malabar is my favorite.
Of all the dark roast coffees that I&amp;rsquo;ve tried (and there have been many; I&amp;rsquo;ve brewed dark roasts almost exclusively over the past few years), the monsooned Malabar is my favorite. It&amp;rsquo;s gives a really nice, very full-bodied cup without overwhelming acidity, which I think translates to a cup that&amp;rsquo;s full but not overpowering in its taste.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://appliedcaffeine.org/blog/modeconfusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://appliedcaffeine.org/blog/modeconfusion/</guid>
      <description>Title: Mode confusion and the recent Boeing 737 MAX-8 crashes Date: 2019-03-15 Category: blog Slug: mode-confusion-boeing-crashes Tags: human factors Summary: A few quick notes on the role that mode confusion may have played in the recent crashes of two Boeing 737 MAX-8 aircraft.
Recent crashes and software changes Recently two Boeing 737 MAX-8 airliners crashed within a few months of each other, killing 357 people (a total loss of life aboard both craft).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://appliedcaffeine.org/blog/navbaritems/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://appliedcaffeine.org/blog/navbaritems/</guid>
      <description>Title: Pelican navbar menu items Date: 2016-04-02 Category: blog Slug: navbaritems Tags: tutorials Summary: Static site generators can greatly reduce the slope of the website creation learning curve. Take advantage of these tools if you are interested in creating your own simple website but want to sidestep manually generating the HTML and CSS on your own.
This is the first in a series of tutorials I&amp;rsquo;ll be writing on the Pelican static site generator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://appliedcaffeine.org/blog/newdirection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://appliedcaffeine.org/blog/newdirection/</guid>
      <description>Title: A new direction for this blog (Updated May 2023) Date: 2021-01-01 Category: blog Slug: a-new-direction Tags: miscellaneous Summary: With the new year, I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about where this blog will go in the future. Below are some thoughts.
Now that I have a full-time job and am out of grad school, I have less time to devote to tinkering and writing about it. I&amp;rsquo;ve consequently been thinking about where this blog should go in the future if I should choose to maintain it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://appliedcaffeine.org/blog/phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://appliedcaffeine.org/blog/phd/</guid>
      <description>Title: Reflections on writing a dissertation Date: 2018-06-19 Category: blog Slug: writing-a-dissertation Tags: dissertation, opinion Summary: Now that my dissertation is complete, I offer my perspective on the process and some advice for prospective PhD candidates.
The dust has settled, the dissertation document is complete and submitted, and for the first time in a few years I don&amp;rsquo;t have the albatross of writing guilt slung around my neck. So I thought I&amp;rsquo;d write about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://appliedcaffeine.org/blog/physicalmanagers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://appliedcaffeine.org/blog/physicalmanagers/</guid>
      <description>Title: We should recommend physical password managers, too Date: 2017-04-24 Category: blog Slug: physical-versus-digital-password-managers Tags: cybersecurity, human factors Summary: Depending on user needs, an actual &amp;ldquo;password book&amp;rdquo; might not be a bad idea. It&amp;rsquo;s certainly better than rampant password reuse.
Sweeping, one-size-fits-all advice on digital security is not a good idea. It&amp;rsquo;s never been a good idea, and as the number and variety of people and devices that come online continue to increase, so goes our need to provide variegated recommendations for security best practices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://appliedcaffeine.org/blog/pihole/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://appliedcaffeine.org/blog/pihole/</guid>
      <description>Title: Installing Pi-hole on a BeagleBoard to block ads Date: 2017-1-4 Category: blog Slug: pi-hole-on-beagleboard Tags: tutorials Summary: Instructions for installing Pi-hole to systematically block advertisements across your network are easy to find, but it gets a little more tricky when using different hardware. Here are some tips to get up and running with a BeagleBoard.
A note to readers I&amp;rsquo;ve updated this post several times after getting comments from readers and helping them troubleshoot their installations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://appliedcaffeine.org/blog/powertop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://appliedcaffeine.org/blog/powertop/</guid>
      <description>Title: PowerTOP at boot and startup scripts Date: 2016-09-3 Category: blog Slug: powertop-and-linux-startup-scripts Tags: tutorials Summary: So, you have a laptop on which you&amp;rsquo;ve installed Linux, and you&amp;rsquo;ve configured and used PowerTOP to reduce the power consumption of said hardware. That&amp;rsquo;s great! The question now becomes: &amp;ldquo;How should I implement these power-saving settings automatically every time I reboot my laptop?&amp;rdquo;
So, you have a laptop on which you&amp;rsquo;ve installed Linux, and you&amp;rsquo;ve configured and used PowerTOP to reduce the power consumption of said hardware.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://appliedcaffeine.org/blog/programcosts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://appliedcaffeine.org/blog/programcosts/</guid>
      <description>Title: Paying for programs in the Age of Free Date: 2016-09-28 Category: blog Slug: paying-for-programs Tags: opinion Summary: If someone is sufficiently motivated, she can find most programs&amp;ndash;or an alternative&amp;ndash;for free. It begs the question: Why would anyone want to pay for a program you could get or otherwise use for free? I present my argument for doing just that &amp;hellip; but there&amp;rsquo;s a catch.
Over a beer, a few friends and I were once talking about the availability of certain software programs within the open-source community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://appliedcaffeine.org/blog/tarrazu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://appliedcaffeine.org/blog/tarrazu/</guid>
      <description>Title: Costa Rican Tarrazu Date: 2016-04-07 Category: blog Slug: tarrazu Tags: coffee Summary: A good first exposure to a medium roast that won&amp;rsquo;t leave you with a bad taste in your mouth.
Some information on the Costa Rican Tarrazu can be found here, but it should be noted I don&amp;rsquo;t have any information (yet) on the origin or estate. If I find it or get it from the roaster, I&amp;rsquo;ll update this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://appliedcaffeine.org/blog/threatmodel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://appliedcaffeine.org/blog/threatmodel/</guid>
      <description>Title: What&amp;rsquo;s in your threat model? Date: 2017-03-7 Category: blog Slug: threat-model Tags: cybersecurity Summary: Everyone should have a threat model, but a bit of thought should go into calibration. Make sure your model is appropriate and that your opsec follows from it.
Since early February, there&amp;rsquo;s been a surge of people giving travel advice in response to recent travel bans, immigration enforcement measures, and stories about people being detained at our borders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://appliedcaffeine.org/blog/time/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://appliedcaffeine.org/blog/time/</guid>
      <description>Title: Learning to value my time Date: 2018-04-02 Category: blog Slug: valuing-time Tags: opinion Summary: This is one of the most important lessons I learned while working from home. If you don&amp;rsquo;t value your own time, who will?
I&amp;rsquo;ve worked from home for the past two years. I&amp;rsquo;m nearly finished with grad school and am in the final stages of dissertation writing, and for the past two years I worked part-time as a remote employee for an engineering company in Pittsburgh, PA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://appliedcaffeine.org/blog/usershaming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://appliedcaffeine.org/blog/usershaming/</guid>
      <description>Title: User shaming is counterproductive for lots of things, including cybersecurity Date: 2017-09-17 Category: blog Slug: stop-user-shaming Tags: human factors, cybersecurity status: draft Summary: Shame is rarely an effective motivation strategy,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://appliedcaffeine.org/blog/wcry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://appliedcaffeine.org/blog/wcry/</guid>
      <description>Title: WCry, ransomware, and the challenge of legacy software Date: 2017-05-17 Category: blog Slug: wcry-and-legacy-software Tags: cybersecurity, systems engineering Summary: If organizations would just stop using Windows XP and patch their software, WCry wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have been an issue. Unfortunately, that&amp;rsquo;s often easier said than done for safety-critical systems built with now-retired software.
Last week the WannaCrypt0r ransomware blew through Europe and Asia, targeting unpatched and legacy Windows systems vulnerable to a code execution bug within its SMB filesharing protocol.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://appliedcaffeine.org/pages/notfound/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://appliedcaffeine.org/pages/notfound/</guid>
      <description>Title: 404: This page has not been found. Status: hidden save_as: 404.html
Unfortunately, the page you were trying to get to cannot be found. Please double-check your desired destination.
If you have definitely reached this page in error, please email me by following the Email link in the navbar at top of the page. Be sure to tell me a bit about what you were trying to do.
Thanks in advance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://appliedcaffeine.org/pages/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://appliedcaffeine.org/pages/publications/</guid>
      <description>Title: Publications slug: publications
This material is presented to ensure timely dissemination of scholarly and technical work.
PLEASE NOTE that the contents disclosed on this page are NOT subject to the Creative Commons licensure agreement covering the rest of this site&amp;rsquo;s contents.
Copyright and all rights therein are retained by authors or by other copyright holders. All persons copying this information are expected to adhere to the terms and constraints invoked by each author&amp;rsquo;s copyright.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
